perishablepress.com 2019-07-31

# Privacy Policy - Perishable Press

Hello. Thank you for visiting. Here’s how we protect your data and respect your privacy. If you have any concerns about your privacy, please contact us by visiting [our contact page](https://perishablepress.com/contact/).

Our website address is `https://perishablepress.com/`

## Our role in your privacy

If you are a Perishable Press customer or subscriber, or just visiting our site, this policy applies to you.

### Our responsibilities

If you are a registered Perishable Press customer or a visitor to our website we act as the “data controller” of personal data. This means we determine how and why your data are processed.

### Your responsibilities

  * Read this Privacy Policy
  * If you are our customer, please also check any agreements between us: they may contain further details on how we collect and process your data.
  * If you provide us with personal information about other people, or if others give us your information, we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us. By submitting the information, you confirm that you have the right to authorize us to process it on your behalf in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## When and how we collect data

From the first moment you interact with Perishable Press, we are collecting data. Sometimes you provide us with data, sometimes data about you is collected automatically. Here’s when and how we do this:

  * You browse any page of our website
  * You contact us via our contact page
  * You use any Perishable Press services
  * You receive emails/messages from us
  * You chat with us for customer support
  * You opt-in to marketing messages
  * You sign up for our free newsletter
  * We call you to provide support

## Types of data we collect

Here is an overview of the types of data that we may collect as you navigate our site and use any of our services or products:

  * Contact details: name, email address, telephone number
  * Purchase information: transaction ID, email address, date
  * Computer information: IP address, user agent, email address
  * Site usage data: URI requests, page response times, errors

### What about really sensitive data?

We never collect any “sensitive data” about you (like racial/ethnic origin, political opinions, religious/philosophical beliefs, genetic data, biometric data, health data, data about your sexual life or orientation, and offenses or alleged offenses).

### What about children’s data?

Perishable Press is intended for use only by those who are 18 years of age or over. We do not target our business at children, and we do not knowingly collect any personal data from any person under 16 years of age.

## How and why we collect your data

The data protection law requires that we use your data only for certain reasons, and where we have a legal basis to do so. Here are the reasons that we collect and use your data:

  * To personalize your experience while using the site
  * To improve the usability and functionality of the site
  * To improve customer service and help resolve any issues
  * To send purchase data to third-party payment processors
  * To personalize communications with our customers
  * To send emails about new features, products, services, and content
  * To remotely activate and deactivate our digital products
  * To facilitate license management for purchased products
  * For login and authentication, and remembering your settings

## Your privacy choices and rights

We collect data from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form. Any data that we request that is not required will be specified as voluntary or optional. Here is an overview of your privacy choices and rights.

### You can choose not to provide us with personal data

If you choose to do this, you can continue to use the website and browse its pages, but we will not be able to process transactions without personal data.

### You can turn off cookies in your browser by changing its settings

You can block cookies by activating a setting on your browser allowing you to refuse cookies. You can also delete cookies through your browser settings. If you turn off cookies, you can continue to use the website and browse its pages, but certain site features (like logging into the Members Area) will not work properly.

### You can ask us not to use your data for marketing

We will inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for marketing and if third parties are involved. You can opt out from marketing by contacting us (see the "Contact Us" section below).

### How to exercise your rights

You can exercise your rights by contacting us via our contact page (see the "Contact Us" section below).

### You have the right to access information we hold about you

This includes the right to request supplementary information about:

  * The types of data we’re processing
  * The purposes of any relevant data processing
  * How long the data will be stored (or the criteria used to determine that period)

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us.

For any such request, we will provide you with the information within 30 days, unless doing so would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others (e.g. another person’s confidentiality or intellectual property rights). We’ll tell you if we can’t meet your request for that reason.

### You have the right to make us correct any inaccurate personal data about you

At any time and for any reason, you may contact us to correct any inaccurate personal information that we may have about you.

### You can object to us using your data for profiling or making automated decisions

We may use your data to determine whether we should let you know information that might be relevant to you (for example, tailoring emails to you based on your behavior). Otherwise, the only circumstances in which we will do this is to provide the Perishable Press service to you.

### You have the right to port your data to another service

We will give you a copy of your data so that you can provide it to another service. We will not do so to the extent that this involves disclosing data about any other individual.

### You have the right to be “forgotten” by us

You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## How do we protect your information?

We have physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the data we collect. Every effort is made to ensure that Perishable Press data is safe and secure. Our business literally depends on solid security, so it is taken _very_ seriously.

### We do not share your information

Other than the third-party vendors listed below, or in situations where we have obtained your consent, we do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer any personally identifiable information to outside parties. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety. Note that you can find the privacy policy for each of our trusted third-party vendors below, in the section “Third parties who process your data”.

### Steps we take to help secure your data

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you submit a request, place an order, or access your personal information. These security measures include, but are not limited to:

  * Password protected directories and databases
  * SSL technology for encrypted data transmission
  * Proprietary security measures that actively protect our servers from threats and malicious activity

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted to our third-party payment processors via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway provider's database, only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and who are required to keep the information confidential. After a transaction, your billing information (credit card numbers, etc.) will NOT be stored on our servers.

### And please remember:

  * You are responsible of your username and password: keep them secret and safe
  * If you believe your privacy has been breached, please contact us immediately
  * You provide personal data at your own risk: unfortunately, no data transmission is guaranteed to be 100% secure

## Where do we store your data?

The data we collect is stored on secure servers in California, US, and may be processed in our office in Washington State, US. Also, data may be collected and stored in any data processing facilities operated by the third parties identified below. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing by us.

## How long do we store your data?

We will archive and stop actively using any personal identifiable information about you within 6 months from the last time you used Perishable Press. We will delete your personal data from our archives no later than 6 years from the last time you used Perishable Press or as agreed with you in a separate contract.

## Third parties who process your data

The following services help us keep Perishable Press running by storing or processing your data on our behalf:

  * Payments: PayPal
  * Payments: Stripe
  * Payments: Coinbase
  * Server: Media Temple

Tech businesses often use third parties to help them host their application, communicate with customers, power their emails etc. We may partner with third parties who we believe are the best in their field at what they do. When we do this, sometimes it is necessary for us to share your data with them in order to get these services to work well. Your data is shared only when strictly necessary and according to the safeguards and good practices detailed in this Privacy Policy.

Here are the details of our main third-party service providers, and what data they collect or we share with them, where they store the data and why they need it:

### Infrastructure

Service provider | Data collected or shared | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Media Temple  
([Privacy Policy](https://mediatemple.net/legal/privacy-policy/)) | 

  * Cookies
  * Contact data
  * Registration data
  * Navigational data
  * Other data that may identify you (as outlined above)

| This is a web hosting provider: we use it to host Perishable Press content and services.  
  
### Payments

Service provider | Data collected or shared | Purpose  
---|---|---  
PayPal, Inc.  
([Privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full)) | 

  * Contact details
  * Financial information
  * Cookies

| This service processes payments for us.  
Stripe, Inc.  
([Privacy policy](https://stripe.com/us/privacy/)) | 

  * Contact details
  * Financial information
  * Cookies

| This service processes payments for us.  
Coinbase, Inc.  
([Privacy policy](https://www.coinbase.com/legal/privacy)) | 

  * Contact details
  * Financial information
  * Cookies

| This service processes payments for us.  
  
### Comments

Service provider | Data collected or shared | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Gravatar  
([Privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/)) | 

  * Email address

| For users who leave comments on the site, an anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are registered. If you have a Gravatar account, an image of your choosing may be displayed next to any comment(s) left by you.  
  
### Others

Service provider | Data collected or shared | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Google Webmaster Tools  
([Privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)) | 

  * Cookies
  * Visitor data

| Google Webmaster Tools (aka Search Console) is a website statistics service: we use it to track general site traffic, so that we resolve any issues and optimize your experience visiting and using our website.  
Google Fonts  
([Privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy)) | 

  * Your IP address
  * Possibly other data, depending on Google

| Google Fonts is a free web service that provides free fonts for web pages. Fonts play an important role in the look and feel of site content.  
  
## How we use cookies

Perishable Press uses cookies to help provide features and services. Unless you disable cookie support in your browser, we (and/or any of our third-party services) may issue cookies when you interact with Perishable Press. These may be “session” cookies, meaning they delete themselves when you leave Perishable Press, or “persistent” cookies which do not delete themselves and help us recognize you when you return so we can provide a tailored service. We list the cookies we use below.

### How can I block cookies?

You can block cookies by disabling cookie support in your browser. You can also delete cookies through your browser settings. If you use your browser settings to disable, reject, or block any cookies, certain parts of our website may not function properly. In some cases, our website may be inaccessible. Please note that where third parties use cookies, we have no control over how those cookies are used. You may contact any third-party vendor for further information.

### Which specific cookies do we use?

Service provider | Key cookies | Purpose  
---|---|---  
Perishable Press | 

  * `PHPSESSID`
  * `wordpress_test_cookie`
  * `wordpress_logged_in_{random-string}`
  * Additional cookies may be set when user leaves a comment
  * Additional cookies may be set when user logs in to their account
  * Additional cookies may be set for local UI features

| These cookies are used to provide basic site functionality, features, and services. For example, the “logged_in” cookie makes it possible to log in to the Members Area. Likewise, if you leave a comment on the site, some additional cookies may be set. Even when no action is taken, local cookies may be used for UI features, like switching themes, toggling zen mode, and so forth.  
  
## Our right to make changes

We reserve the right to make changes to our Privacy Policy at any time and with no prior notice. Please revisit this page for the latest information. We will notify our customers with any major changes via email.

## Contact Us

Thanks for reading our Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or concerns, feel free to contact us via our [Contact Page](https://perishablepress.com/contact/).
  *[SSL]: Secure Sockets Layer
  *[UI]: User Interface
